crochetville.org 2015-10-13

# Privacy Policy - Crochetville

**PRIVACY POLICY EFFECTIVE 12/21/14**

Your personal privacy is very important to us at Crochetville. We do not sell, rent, give, or otherwise divulge your personally-identifiable information (PII) to other parties outside of Crochetville administrative staff. Please read our privacy policy for more information on how we use and protect your personal information. We want you to have a clear understanding of our privacy policy.

The Crochetville forum software collects personal information to provide you with an efficient, enjoyable, and customized forum experience. The only personal information we collect is what is necessary to achieve this purpose.

We do not allow registrations by children under the age of 13. A child under the age of 13 must have a parent or guardian create an account and visit the forum under the supervision of parent or guardian.

Any non-registered member is able to browse the majority of the Crochetville forum site (with the exception of several members-only folders) with anonymity: you do not need to tell us who you are or give us any personally-identifiable information about yourself. Once you register an account on Crochetville, you are no longer anonymous to the administrative staff.

When you register an account with Crochetville, you are first required to enter a birthdate (to comply with internet safety laws that prevent children from signing up for forums without a parent's permission). You are also required to provide us with a valid, working email address. While you are an active member at Crochetville, you must keep a valid, working email address on file with your account in case we ever need to contact you (and so that you will receive email notifications of Private Messages and posts in threads to which you have subscribed). Your IP address is also logged whenever you register and subsequently post to the forum. This is the only personally-identifiable information that is required to register an account.

Once you have registered an account, you may choose (at your own discretion) to enter other personal information in your profile that can be viewed by other Crochetville members. (Only registered members can view another member's profile information.)

Crochetville's Invision Power Services forum software also uses cookies to help personalize your forum experience by keeping track of which messages you have read, your Private Messages, threads to which you have subscribed, and so on. We also use cookies to enable you to enter your password only once during a session (if you click the "Remember Me" button when logging in).

Personal information stored on your computer cannot be collected via cookies. However, personal information you may have provided to this site may be tied to cookies.

Crochetville respects your privacy and will not share your personally identifiable information collected at this site with third parties except for the following limited circumstances: (1) you have given us your consent to share the information; (2) we need to seek the assistance of the abuse department at your ISP [any IP address you've used to connect to Crochetville] to stop disruptions you are causing to our forum, (3) in response to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process including in the event of a complaint or legal action arising from any message posted by you; and (4) we believe the health or well-being of you or another member is threatened.

**Crochetville Order Processing**

To comply with Regulation (EU) No 1042/2013, Crochetville may now collect the following personal data when you place an order with us: 1) full name, 2) billing address, 3) phone number, 4) email address, and 5) VAT number. This information is used solely for the purposes of order processing, invoicing, and tax law compliance. Crochetville may need to share this information with US and EU tax authorities when preparing and documenting VAT returns as required by law. Your information will not be shared with anyone else nor used for any other purpose.

Independent designers make their patterns available for sale in our digital pattern store. When you make a purchase, our software makes available to each designer a record the date you purchased their pattern and your Crochetville member name.

**MaxMind**

Crochetville utilizes the MaxMind service to comply with Regulation (EU) No 1042/2013 regarding VAT for sales of digital services. MaxMind is a participant in US-EU and US-Swizerland Safe Harbor programs. You can read [MaxMind's Privacy Poicy here](https://www.maxmind.com/en/privacy_policy).

**Paypal**

Crochetville uses Paypal to process all online payments. You can read [Paypal's Privacy Policy here](https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full).

**Google Advertising Cookie and Privacy Policy**

  * Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on Crochetville.
  * Google's use of the DART cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to Crochetville users based on the user's visits to Crochetville and/or other sites on the Internet.
  * Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

**Third Party Ads**  
Crochetville may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/faqs.asp).

For a list of vendors that have been certified by Google AdSense for third-party ads, [click here](https://www.google.com/adsense/support/bin/answer.py?answer=94149). You may visit those vendor websites to opt out of cookies (if the vendor or ad network offers this capability). Users can opt out of some, but not all, of these cookies in one location at the Network Advertising Initiative's opt-out website at [www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp](http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

**Amazon**  
Crochetville is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to amazon.com. Link: [Amazon.com's Privacy Notice](http://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=468496).

**VigLink**  
Crochetville uses VigLink to automatically affiliate commercial links. Link: [More information about VigLink and the option to opt-out](http://www.viglink.com/static/policies/ftc).

**Chitika**  
Crochetville uses Chitika to display ads to select traffic. You can opt out of Chitika here: <http://chitika.com/privacy>.

**Criteo**  
Crochetville uses Criteo to display ads to select traffic. You can [view Criteo's privacy policy and opt out](http://www.criteo.com/us/privacy-policy).

_We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy from time to time without notice. Please review the Privacy Policy from time to time so that you will be apprised of any changes._
